## **Gideon Miles Oluku**

Mobile No: 07783180169 Email Address: Milesoluku@gmail.com GitHub: github.com/milesuno

Web Developer and Business Graduate, with a background in agile development and experience in start-up business development. I am a highly motivated self-starter. I have always been passionate about bringing ideas into reality, demonstrated in my own self-fund projects. This has been a major driver in my interest in technology, as the scope of development is almost unlimited. I feel my unique experience in both business studies and web development would make me an effective addition to a growing organisation.

### **SKILLS:**

- Front End: HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, React
- Backend: Node.js, MongoDB, Mongo Atlas
- Tools: Trello, Glitch, GitHub, Slack, Git, Terminal, Postman
- Methodologies: Agile Project Management, Scrum

### **EDUCATION:**

## Full Stack Web Developer - Boot Camp

**Code Your Future** 

2018 – 2019: London

Knowledge: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React, MongoDB, JSON, RESTful API, HTTP requests.

### **PROJECTS**:

## Glossary:

<u>Link:</u> https://github.com/ahmedahashim/CYF-Glossary

<u>Scenario</u>: My team and I, we responsible for delivering a glossary for technology-based technical terms. We were a team of 4 with a deadline of 24 days. I was the Project Manager and Front-End developer for the project. We successfully completed a working product on time and demonstrated its functionality to stakeholders.

Contribution: UX/UI design, Prototyping, Front-end Development, Project Management.

## See Your Future - Capgemini:

Link: https://github.com/eddientim/CYF-CAPGEMINI

Scenario: My team and I entered a competition hosted by Capgemini. Our object was to deliver a platform to connect inexperienced developers with companies, helping them to find out more about the industry and job roles. I was the Project Manager and Front-End developer for the project. We were a team of 8 and had a 30-day deadline. We successfully delivered a working product meeting the deadline and won 'Best Engineered' and 'Most Innovative' awards - 2 of 3 awards available. I was voted by my peers to receive the 'Hero Helper' award, due to my contributions.

Contribution: UX/UI, Prototyping, Front-end Development, Project Management.

## Agile Project Management - Foundation University of Northampton

2017 – 2018 Northampton

#### Key Modules:

- Philosophy and principles of Agile.
- Roles and responsibilities within an Agile project.
- Process and Products produced during an Agile project.
- Planning, control, tracking, and testing concepts
- Agile Practices: MoSCoW, DSDM timeboxing, Workshops, Modelling, Iterative Development.

## **BA Business Studies Degree**

## **University of Northampton**

2014 – 2017 Northampton

Achieved: 2:1 BA Business Studies Degree

## **EXPERIENCE**:

## **Front End Developer**

#### InvestCloud

2019 - Present London

Description: I build user and admin portals for Financial Institutions:

#### **Duties Include:**

- Building Prototypes, MVP's and Deploying Front End Designs
- Debugging, Troubleshooting
- Attend daily stand-ups, timeline and scoping meetings

#### Intern

#### Onfido

2019 - 2019 London

<u>Description</u>: I interned at Onfido - and document verification company. I shadowed all key departments within the organisation.

#### **Duties Include:**

• Interviewing and shadowing: Technical PM, Product Manager, Product Designer, Full Stack Developer, Machine Learning Engineer, Business Intelligence.

## **Creative Director**

## **BarterAnything**

2017 - Present London

<u>Link</u>: https://barteranything.com/

## **Duties Include:**

- Development:
  - I was responsible for: Business and System requirement planning, followed by UX/UI Design, Wireframing, and Prototyping.
- Management:
  - I was responsible for: Appointing project roles, Creating project delivery plan and Timeboxing Planning, Hosting Daily stand-up meetings and workshops. I also managed business acceptance testing and creating models for stakeholders.
- Finance:
  - I was responsible for: Acquiring business partnerships and funding (Santander, O2, University of Northampton) and Managing All Project Budgeting.

#### Sales Consultant/Team Leader

#### **Carphone Warehouse**

2018- 2019 London

#### **Duties Include:**

- Administration: Shop and Back office maintenance Banking, Assisting with Workforce deployment
- Team Leading: Supervising Team, Delegating work, Opening and Closing Store.

# President of the Investment Society University of Northampton

2016 – 2017 Northampton

#### Duties Include:

• Administration and Events Management: Increasing members by 400% from various promo events.

- Team Leading: Work allocation to maintenance weekly classes teaching investment fundamentals.
- Producing and delivering presentations: Hosting weekly meetings delivering classes to students.

## **VOCATIONAL WORK:**

## **Coding Teaching Assistant**

#### **Code Your Future**

2019 - Present London

<u>Description</u>: I volunteer to teach and assist in Code Your Future - a charity Coding Bootcamp for refugees and underprivileged individuals during the weekend.

#### **Duties Include:**

- Assisting in class organisation and delivery
- Assisting students with debugging and programming fundamentals

## **Entrepreneurial Programme**

#### The Prince's Trust

2018 - 2019 London

My passion for developing my Entrepreneurial Skills led me to attend courses and workshops covering:

- Business Development and Digital Product Development
- Pitching and Negotiating
- Finance and Budgeting
- Business Law and Employment Law

## **REFERENCES:**

Reference on Request